Ratna Singh

Automation Testing Engineer

Having experience of 5.7 years in developing and maintaining overall test methodology and strategy Documenting Test plans, Test cases and editing, executing Tests cases and Test scripts Using Automation (web and API), and Analyzed User Requirements and Technical Specifications.





raghavipriya2215@gmail.com



New Delhi, India

+91 7702546822

EDUCATION

BSc in Information Science and Telecommunication, Ravenshaw University With First Division in 2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Test Engineer Wipro Ltd

Oct 2015 - June 2019

Automation Testing and Manual Testing

- Responsible for Automation testing and Manual testing for the Northwest Passage and LabCorp Hospital.
- Creating Test Plan, Test Scenarios, Test Cases and Test Scripts to validate source and Target data
- Perform Functionality Testing, Regression Testing and Exploratory Testing.
- Created and Enhanced the Test Cases using Element Locators.
- Executed the Selenium Test cases and reporting the defects.

Associate Software Testing Engineer Sonyo Management

June 2021-January2022

Manual / Automation Testing

- Tested over 70 test scenarios under agile process for Tech Mahindra WOSAT Application of telecommunication domain.
- Established proper team communication that identified, triaged, reproduced and fixed found issued using JIRA increasing the overall workflow by 25% for the Tech Mahindra Project
- Cooperated with developers to design 50+ test cases for regular maintenance and enhancements with the help of selenium with java

QA Lead

Nityo Infotech

Feb 2022-May 2022

Manual /Automation Testing

- Created test scripts using WebDriver.
- Involved in test scripts review.
- Running batch execution and sending status report to higher management.
- Preparing and Executing Batch Test Suite through TestNG.
- Verify the Automated test Result, and Logging the Defect in Jira and updating status to the higher management.
- Experience in debugging and modification of existing scripts.



Test Analyst ITC Infotech

08/2022 - 06/2023

Manual/Automation Testing

- Worked as a Test Analyst with 4 members in the Team.
- Framework Development of the Application.
- Creation of Test Plan, gathering the requirement, creating the test cases
- Creation of the Automation Scripts.
- Bug tracking, raising bugs in Jira, Creating Test Cycle in Zephyr, attending daily standup calls, retrospectives meetings.
- Performing Automation testing, database testing using SQL developer.

INTERESTS

Reading books Watching movies

learning new and innovative things